We have this UML state diagram.
And the first thing we are asked to do is answer
in which non-composite state, does every flow
of this diagram start?
To answer this question, we start looking
from the outside.
And in the outside, you see, the only entrance
to this diagram is this starting state.
And this starting state is pointing to this
composite state, which has no name.
So, this means now this state is going to
be activated.
And since the arrow is not pointing explicitly
directly at any of these two non-composite
states, this means we go the standard way.
The standard way is to also look here in the
outside, and we see the only entrance is this
starting state.
And it's pointing to this non-composite state
F. So, the answer is F.
This means every time we're going to use this
diagram, every time is going to be activated,
the first non-composite state to be active
is F. Now, for the second part of the question
of the task, it says give for each of the
following successions of triggers the sequence
of states as they are visited one after another.
And now, as I said, F is the starting state,
is the first state to be visited.
This means it's going to be the first state
in every solution for these sequences.
And now for the first sequence, it starts
with A, and only A going out from our active
states is this one here, there is no other
A going out from this composite state, there's
only this one going out from F.
This means after F we have G. And now again,
we have H. So, this H only occurs here, it's
going out from G. There are no other Hs here.
And this means the next state that we are
going to visit is E. Next in the sequence,
we have K and K is here.
There are no other Ks around.
So, K brings us back to this composite state.
And this arrow of K is not pointing explicitly,
directly to any of these non-composite states.
But rather it's pointing to this composite
state, the big one.
And this means we go the standard way, which
is again, we say this state is active, it's
visited now.
And we search here, we see that the only entrance
is the starting state here, which goes to
F, the arrow is pointing at F. Now the last
element in the sequence is A, and A takes
us from F to G.
This is the solution for this sequence.
Now for the next sequence, again, we have
F at the start.
And the sequence starts with A, A takes us
to G and then we have H, H takes us to E once
again.
This time we have H and H is going to take
us to this composite state, this big one.
And since this arrow is pointing explicitly,
and directly at D, this means D is active,
it's visited.
It's going to be visited no matter what happens.
But at the same time as I said this big composite
state is also active and it has regions.
So, this means in addition to D in this part
here, we need to look for the standard way
of going which is A because the starting state
is pointing at A, the arrow is pointing at
A and now this means we have two non-composite
states A and D being visited at the same time.
And this is how we express it, this is how
we write it.
And the last element of the sequence is B,
there are no Bs here.
So, this means we stay in A. But for D if you
use B you go to C. And this means after using
B, we are in A and C at the same time.
This is the final solution.
And now we do this sequence.
Again, we start with F, and then we have A,
A takes us to G, and we have H, H takes
us to E. And then we have H again. H takes us to
this composite state, the same thing happens.
And we are in A and D at the same time.
This time we have A and A does nothing for
D, we stay in D, but it takes us from A to
B.
This means now we are in B and D at the same
time.
And then we have B. B takes us from D to C
and it keeps us in B, it doesn't change anything
here.
And this means we are now visiting B and C
at the same time.
And the last element of the sequence is K.
But you might wonder how can we do K while
we are in B and C?
Well, this is possible because as I said before,
it's not just B and C, which are being visited.
Actually we are visiting also this composite
state which contains them.
And from this composite state, this big one
here we have an arrow with K.
So, it is possible to use K and go here.
Now we have this composite state active and
the arrow is not pointing directly.
It's not pointing explicitly at any of the
non-composite states F and G.
We go the standard way which is starting with
F. So, this means this is how the solution
looks like.
This is the final solution.